Deepa Tamraparani

LinkedIn Profile Tamraparani.D@gmail.com +49 176 470 724 14 Berlin, Germany

Summary

Passionate Individual with 8 years of professional experience as IT Consultant at Sapiens in the field of Insurance and Java JEE applications. Le Wagon Data Science graduate with project experience in the field of Start up evaluation. WHU Masters in Business administration focused on Entrepreneurship and Innovation

Experience

Data Science Student - Le Wagon Coding School

2023|07 - present

- · Learned Data Science with Python; Data Analytics with SQL, BigQuery, Pandas, Numpy, and Matplotlib
- · Machine Learning with Scikit-learn; Deep Learning with TensorFlow Keras
- · Statistics with Scipy, Seaborn and Statsmodels

Technical Team Lead for Backend Engineering team - Sapiens Germany GmbH Berlin

2020 - 2023 | 08

- · Supervised Agile software development lifecycle, Hands on Coding and Code Reviews
- · Creation of intricate infrastructure that supports critical insurance processes

Technical Consultant / Software Development - Sapiens Singapore

2018 - 2020

- · Designing Algorithms and using JEE to develop high Quality Insurance Software in intense Agile development framework
- · Feature Engineering to enable modeling of risk assessment and optimising Claim Loss
- · Integration of Google Analytics and Report Generation for the Marketing department
- · Demonstrated leadership skills by successfully managing diverse international teams

Software Developer - Sapiens India

2014 - 2020

- · Received Product Development Training in Israel
- · Implementation of Solution prototypes for Prospective Customers
- · Hands On Coding and Timed deliverables in fast paced project implementation in single handed and large teams

Software Developer - NTT DATA First Apex India

2012 - 2014

 $\cdot \ \text{Responsible for building core product modules including Document Generation System}, \ Workflow \ System$

Skills

Technical Skills -

- · Data Science with Python; Data Analytics with SQL, BigQuery, Pandas, Numpy, and Matplotlib
- · Machine Learning with Scikit-learn; Deep Learning with TensorFlow Keras
- · Statistics with Scipy, Seaborn and Statsmodels
- · Java JEE, python, Web services, SQL Server, gcloud, Docker, Git
- · Machine learning, MLOps, Software Engineering, Scrum, Insurance

Education

Graduated as Bachelors in Computer Science - BMS Institute of Technology(VTU)

2008 - 2012

 \cdot Learn, develop and evaluate an algorithms

Master in Business Administration - WHU - Otto Beisheim School of Management

2020 - present

· Exploring various facets of Business centered around Artificial Intelligence